gtricks.com 2019-12-08

# Privacy

## We take your privacy seriously.

We do not sell, trade or rent your personal information to third parties. We collect only the standard information required to run our apps or to provide a better experience. 

This privacy policy covers all the services, apps, extensions, content and other offerings by Gtricks. It was last updated on 28th July 2017. Update change was formatting.

At Gtricks (“We”, “Us”, “Our”), we respect the client’s (“You”, “Your” or “User”) privacy and take protecting it seriously. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which our Clients have engaged us.

**Do you collect passwords?**

We use Google sign-in to authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your email address. _We do not collect or have access to your password._ The information you provide is held in strict confidence. We collect this information to generate your user license, send payment receipts and communicate with the user about product updates etc. 

Our services use the Google OAuth 2.0 protocol for authentication without requiring the user to share their login credentials with us. OAuth also allows secure access to the user’s data, as required by the add-ons, and the data resides strictly inside your Google account. We do not store any of your account data on our servers.

**What information does Gtricks collect? How is this information used?**

Below is the comprehensive list of all type of information we may collect but not necessarily collect. For example, for our blog articles, we do not collect email address but for our apps, we might require the email address to send reports. 

Personal: We collect personal information from users including (at minimum) first and last names, and a Google Apps email address to be used as a login. When a user registers online for our products, we will try to verify the identity. We will also collect billing and payment information via third-party payment partners. With your email address, we will send you periodic information, offers, and other content. You can opt out of these emails at any time, but a few service emails like confirmation emails, billing receipts etc. will still be sent to you for an optimum experience. We use the information collected to deliver services, update our records, communicate with you about products and services, and generally maintain your accounts with us. We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, as needed to provide you services, to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. If you wish to cancel your account or want we no longer use your information you can opt out by contacting us. We do not sell, trade, or rent your personal information to third parties. We might share them as described in this privacy policy but only to give you a better experience like conducting surveys on your email address.

Business (Information includes app data, documents, files, configuration settings and any other business information stored on Gtricks): Information that is collected by us is considered confidential. We will not view this information except as necessary to appropriately support the service or as required by law. We will not view Business Information, except as necessary to appropriately support the service, for the purpose of anticipating, diagnosing, supporting or resolving any problems that might limit or disrupt the quality of our customers’ service experience or as required by law.

Partners: In some cases, we provide services or sell product lines jointly with other businesses. For these co-branded offerings in which a third party is involved in your transactions, we will sometimes share or jointly collect customer information related to those transactions with that third party. On the co-branded registration pages we will state who is collecting or receiving the information and whose privacy statement governs its use so that you will know at the time you create your account exactly how your information will be used. If you are registered with Gtricks through a partnership and you request to opt out of receiving promotional and other updates, you can optout by contacting us. We will also provide your email address to that partner so that they may also discontinue sending you messages on behalf of Gtricks.

Session Records: To maintain our quality of service and to assist in the analysis of product performance, we may also gather data on connection information, including the timing and size of all packets sent over the Internet during a session. The gathered information is used only to ensure the highest quality experience possible when using Gtricks products and services.

Security: Gtricks also collects certain standard information about your computer for security and identification purposes. This information may include: IP addresses, domain names, access times, cookies and other unique identifying information of machines that have our software downloaded and installed on them. This information is used for the operation of the service, to identify and protect our customers and to control unauthorized use or abuse of our services. All information is encrypted during transmission and is stored securely on our servers.

Surveys: In addition to required member information, we may conduct surveys and ask users to volunteer demographic information to be used on an aggregate basis for internal market research, presentation to advertisers and joint research projects with outside companies involved in product development. We use such information to better focus our product and personalize the scope of services offered to each individual user.

Web Analytics: We continuously improve our websites and utilize different web analytic tools to help us do so. We are interested in how visitors use our websites, what they like and dislike, and where they have problems. We also use web analytic tools on our mobile applications to help gather non-personally identifiable data about download and application usage. In our use of web analytics, we do collect GeoLocation data, but it is only on an aggregate basis and not tied to any individual. The web beacons used in connection with our web analytics services do not share any personally identifiable information about our website and application visitors with third parties. Our tools may gather data such as what browser a person uses, what operating systems are used, what is downloaded, and what content, products, and services are reviewed when visiting or registering for services at one of our websites or mobile applications. This information is used solely to assist Gtricks in maintaining a more effective and useful website for our customers. We track aggregate traffic patterns throughout our site but we do not correlate this information with personally identifiable data about individual users. We track domain names, browser types and MIME type. Such information will not be passed to third parties without your prior consent unless where required by applicable law.

**Why is my information needed?**  
Gtricks products are web based; because of this, they may require some information like first and last names, billing contact information, and a Google Apps account as a login. Therefore, at a minimum, we may require such necessary information in order to establish your account with us.

**With whom does Gtricks share the information?**  
Ensuring your privacy is important to us. We do not sell, trade or rent your personal information to third parties. Gtricks applications and services by necessity require us to provide some of your information to third parties. We may occasionally employ other companies to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include processing credit card payments, sending postal mail and email, analyzing data and providing marketing assistance. They have access to personal information needed only to perform their functions and may not use it for any other purpose. Furthermore, they must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Also, in the event that Gtricks or the majority of its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets. Gtricks does not control the practices of our affiliates. If you have questions about how affiliates use the information gathered when you link to them, please read their privacy policies. 

Links to other sites: This website may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Gtricks. Please be aware that we, Gtricks, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

**How does Gtricks protect my information from loss, misuse or alteration?**  
Gtricks has implemented commercially reasonable precautions designed to protect the web sites and applications it hosts and the information it collects from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. Nevertheless, we remind you that no security measure is perfect. Gtricks applications are accessed via Google Apps user accounts. Gtricks is not liable for loss of passwords due to user carelessness. If you lose control over your Google account, you may lose control over your personally identifiable information. If you believe your Google Account has been compromised, we recommend that you immediately change your password or activate Google’s 2 step authentication.

**How long does Gtricks retain data?**  
Gtricks currently retains all user and business data indefinitely, until you specifically delete the data or shut down your Gtricks account.

**Who can I ask if I have additional questions?**  
Gtricks is committed to respecting your privacy. This Online Privacy Policy describes the privacy practices for Gtricks applications and their website. In case, you have additional questions, feel free to use the [Contact](https://www.gtricks.com/contact/) page or mail us at 89FB, Scheme 94, Indore-452001, Madhya Pradesh, India.

Also see [Disclaimer](https://www.gtricks.com/disclaimer) and [Terms of Service](https://www.gtricks.com/tos).
